Literatura de Cordel collection, 1918-1995
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Profane Tales., 1918-1995.
  - Title: Aos trabalhadores e ao povo brasileiro Author: Francisco Zênio Illustrator: signed ZENIO Publisher: Secretaria de Cultura e Turismo da Prefeitura Municipal de Juazeiro do Norte Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 1987. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: História da importância do CEAG no Cariri Author: Abraão Batista Illustrator: signed ABB Publisher: A. Batista Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 1987. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: Uma festa de vaquejada em Juazeiro do Norte Author: Abraão Rodrigues Illustrator: signed Stênio Publisher: unknown Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., after 1960. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: O encontro de Tancredo com Tiradentes no céu Author: Expedito Sebastião da Silva Publisher: Secretaria de Cultura e Turismo Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: Encontro do Presidente Tancredo Neves com Getulio Vargas Author: Francisco Zênio Illustrator: signed ZENIO Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., after 1985. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: Delírio de amor Author: Antonio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed but illegible Publisher: unknown Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: O exemplo do menino que falou no ventre da mãe Author: Hélio Cavenaghi Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, HCAVENAGHI., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Title: A genialidade de Da Vinci Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Publisher: G. F. da Silva., 1987. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Getúlio Vargas e o Estado Novo Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustrator: Zé Roberto Publisher: R. S. Helena., after 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O homem que comeu o pão de açucar no Rio de Janeiro Author: Expedito F. Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: R. Gomes Artes Gráficas Place: Rio de Janeiro Other: acrostic, EXPEDITO., 1985. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O homem que matou uma onça de chicote pensando ser um cachorro Author: Minelvino Francisco Silva Illustrator: signed MFS Publisher: M. F. Silva Place: Itabuna, Bahia., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O linchamento de 5 ladrões de carros em Ipiau Author: Minelvino Francisco Silva Illustrator: signed MFS Publisher: unknown., 27 de dezembro de 1986. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A luta de Iracema mocó de cima Author: Iracema Gomes de Carvalho Illustrator: signed MINELVINO Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A volta do galinho Author: Manoel Santa Maria Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown Place: Araruama., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Tem mais partido político que xuxu na perreira Author: José Roque M. Gonçalves Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: R. Gomes Artes Gráficas Place: Rio de Janeiro., 1986. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Tancredo e Sarney Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustrator: signed MARCELO, ZENIO Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro., 1985. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O administrador que foi demitido por que deu água aos pobres Author: unknown Illustrator: signed but illegible Publisher: Movimento Brasileiro de Cordel., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    "Para senador PFL Benedito Domingos" on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Discussão de Collor de Mello com Brizola Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: G. F. da Silva., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Morreu o rei do baião Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Publisher: G. F. da Silva., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Nova república novas medidas e novo Brasil Governo José Sarney Author: Gonçalo Gonalves Bezerra (Poeta Gongon) Publisher: FENACREPC Place: Brasília, DF., 1986. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A cachaça e o cachaceiro Author: Jotamaro Illustrator: signed Jotamaro 88 Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL) Place: Fortaleza, Ceará Other: acrostic, JOAO AMARO., 1988. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Antonio Galheiro, o filho de Zé Corninho Author: Otávio Menezes Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL) Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A briga do trocador com a nêga do Pirambu Author: Jotamaro Illustrator: signed Jotamaro 88 Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL) Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 1988. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Brasil X Chile; Rojas o goleiro ator Author: Guaipuan Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL) Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O cambista que fêz tira-gosto com a orelha da mulher Author: Otávio Menezes Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL) Place: Fortaleza, Ceará Other: 2a edição., 30/01/89. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A história de Chico Mendes; o defensor da floresta Author: Horácio Custódio de Sousa Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará Other: acrostic, HORACIO., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Cante cá que eu canto lá Author: Chico Fábio Illustrator: signed Chico Fábio 89 Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL)., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Ceará campeão 89 Author: João Amaro Publisher: JAFILM., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Advertisement for Ja Film Fotografias on rear wrapper.
  - Title: A chegada de Luiz Gonzaga no céu Author: Otávio Menezes Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará ,lb/>., 20/09/89. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A coisa é diferente com Lula pra Presidente Author: Vescencio Fernandes Illustrator: signed Armando 89 Publisher: Livraria Gabriel Place: Fortaleza, Ceará Other: 2a edição., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Nicanor é um grande inventor, invente você também Author: Franklin Maxado Illustrator: unsigned Series: Projeto Tecnologia Socialmente Apropriada Publisher: IRDEB/CAR Place: Salvador, Bahia., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Aumento das passagens Author: Zé Gamela Illustrator: signed Martos Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Encontro de Zizi Gavião e Lindalva no Largo do Machado no Rio de Janeiro Author: Zizi Gavião Illustrator: Gilvan Santos Publisher: unknown Place: Curitiba, Pr., 1986. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Pelo amor da natureza Author: Costa Sena Illustrator: Otávio Menezes Publisher: GEO Studio Other: 3a edição., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A relação dos cornos brasileiros Author: Guaipan Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: CECORDEL., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A queda do babão Author: Jotamaro Illustrator: Jotamaro 88 Publisher: CECORDEL Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 1988. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O sofrer do boiadeiro Author: Vera Maria Oliveira Illustrator: unknown Publisher: CECORDEL Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A trajetória do rei do baião Author: Paulo de Tarso B. Gomes Illustrator: Otávio Menezes Publisher: Livraria Feira do Livro Place: Fortaleza, Ceará Other: 2a edição., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Todo o Brasil chorou com a morte de Luiz Author: Otávio Menezes Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 04/08/89. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A terrível cena a morte do Padre Bernardo Author: Zé Vicente Illustrator: José Lourenço signed JL Publisher: Lira Nordestina Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 2/06/86. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A língua da faladeira Author: Otávio Menezes Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: O. Menezes Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 25/05/89. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A morte de Luiz Gonzaga Author: Jotamaro Publisher: unknown., after 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A morte do rei de baião Author: Paulo de Tarso Publisher: unknown., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O mundo pegando fogo Author: Zizi Gavião Editor: Otávio Menezes Illustrator: O. Menezes Publisher: Livro Patativa do Assaré, CERES Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 1987. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Pirata de Iracema Author: Costa Sena Illustrator: signed MANO Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: As preces de uma velha vitalina Author: Jotamaro Illustrator: signed Jotamaro Publisher: CECORDEL., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: A prisão do pistoleiro Mainha e seu 1o julgamento Author: Otávio Menezes Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: O PX comprou um anu pensando ser uma Grauna Author: Guaipuan Illustrator: signed Carlo Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará Other: 3a edição., 1987. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Fique com quem sempre esteve ao seu lado Pedro Porfírio para deputado Author: Expedito da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: E. Silva., after 1950. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Galope a beira-mar e gemedeira pra um poeta; marinheiro aposentado também da onda do cordel Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed ABC Publisher: unknown Place: São Paulo., 1984. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Golpes do destino Author: Nilton José da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., 1989. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Title: Pobre só leva fumo Author: Chiquinho do Pandeiro Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: Expedito F. Silva Place: Rio de Janeiro., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Frustrações de um sertanejo Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustrator: signed Santa Helena 1980 Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro Other: 9a edição. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Acabou-se o que era doce Author: Edgar N. Batista Publisher: Gráfica Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O alcool sepulta em vida Author: José Geraldo da Silva Gomes Illustrator: signed AA, J.BORGES Publisher: Grupo A.A. Place: Limoeiro, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Arraes governa de novo Author: José Bento da Silva Publisher: unknown Place: Ribeirão., 25/8/86. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Boêmios no bar pirata Author: Paulo Montezuma Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown Place: Recife, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O candidato do povo é Jarbas Author: José Francisco Borges Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, PE., 01/01/89. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Data from Folha de São Paulo included on rear wrapper.
  - Title: A esperança está de volta Author: Zé da Feira Illustrator: J. Borges Publisher: J. Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., 1986. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Este livro vai mostrar quem é Bernardo Cintura Author: Orlando Folheteiro Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: Gráfica Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A guerra no oriente, ou, O inferno no Iraque Author: José Francisco Borges Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: J. Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., 27/1/91. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Frente de libertação do bonito Author: unknown Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O filho do Valentão do Mundo e a Princesa Corinea Author: Expedito F. Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A história do metrô em Pernambuco Authors: José Cazino da Silva Filho, Heleno Silva Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A poesia popular e a farsa colorida Author: Alagoano Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O valor que o matuto tem Author: Amaro Rufino Illustrator: J. Borges Publisher: J. Borges., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O trem vai voltar Author: Luiz Gonzaga de Lima Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: unknown., 1985. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A vida e a estória de Paulo Porrete Author: Naira de Aguiar Rossiter Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: Gráfica Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A vida de caboclo Author: Simão Pedro dos Santos Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: unknown Place: Bezerros, PE., 1984. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: XXVI Congresso brasileiro de cerâmica, Uma noite brasileira Author: José Francisco Borges Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: unknown Place: Recife, PE., 1982. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Pelo povo, trabalho, Deputado Federal Luiz Piauhlino, Deputado Estadual Denildo Author: José Francisco Borges Illustrator: signed J. Borges Publisher: Gráfica Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: As perguntas do rei e as respostas de Camões, As palhaçadas de Pedro Malazarte Author: Severino Gonçalves de Oliveira, Francisco Sales Areda Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Other: acrostics, CIRILO, FSALES., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Homenagem ao 2o anversário da Academia Brasileira de Literatura de Cordel: Cordel é Cultura Author: multiple authors Publisher: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Authors include: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva, Joaquim Batista de Sena, Francisco C. do Nascimento, Manoel Santa Maria, Marlos de Herval L. da Silva, Sepalo Campelo, Manoel Messias.
  - Title: Fortaleza do passado e do futuro Author: Joaquim Batista da Sena Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 21/05/90. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Porque os discos voadores baixam em Morro do Chapéu Author: Chico Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Oficinas do Correiro do Sertão Place: Morro do Chapéu, Bahia Other: acrostic, CHICOLEITE., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O cursilho e a Bahia Author: Frei Urbano Gregório de Souza Publisher: Escola Gráfica Nossa Senhora de Lorêto Place: Salvador, Bahia., after 1968. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: É Jarbas Author: Lamartine Morais Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Recife., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A missa do vaqueiro vira cordel Author: Ivanildo Vila Nova Publisher: GCL Gráfica Place: Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Corno, bicha e sapatão é o assunto da ocasião Author: Edgar N. Batista Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Gravatã, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Governador é Jarbas Author: Oliveira de Panelas Publisher: unknown., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Election data from Folha de São Paulo on rear wrapper.
  - Title: Tancredo: 39 dias de agonia Author: Sá de João Pessoa Publisher: unknown., 1985. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Sarney congela o verão com seu pacote pesado Author: Manoel Santa Maria Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown Place: Araruama, RJ., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A prisão do João do Norte na Feira de São Cristovão Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: A posse do presidente e o impacto do plano Brasil novo Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: O louco do volante Author: Sá de João Pessoa Illustrator: signed JOEL Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Cadê o Halley Author: Sá de João Pessoa Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Rio de Janeiro., 1986. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Arquimedes: o maior dos sabios da antiguidades Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: Academia Brasileira de Literatura., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Antônio Silvino com Lampião no Inferno Author: José Arnaldo da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Para ver a barca andar em defesa do Rio São Francisco Author: Chico Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Gráfica e Editora Ereba Ltda. Place: Pírapora, MG Other: acrostic, CHICOLEITE., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Encômios à memória de Feria de Santana Author: Sebastião Pereira Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Plataforma de um poeta de cordel imortável Author: Raimundo Santa Helena Illustrator: signed ABL, NELY Publisher: R. S. Helena Place: Rio de Janeiro., 1988. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Title: Dina Sfat a guerrilheira da arte Author: Hélio Dutra Publisher: Academia Brasileira de Literatura de Cordel Place: Rio de Janeiro., after 1989. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O trágico desastre que causou a morte do deputado Ulysses Guimarães Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Publisher: A. A. dos Santos Place: Campina Grande, Paraíba Other: acrostic, AALVES., 1992. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: As novas do Brasil novo e as promessas coloridas Author: Marcus Antonio Lutzen Illustrator: M. A. Lutzen, Lucena Publisher: unknown Place: Campina Grande, Paraíba., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Vida e morte do Gonzaga Author: Eduardo Manoel dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1990. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Unidos bonito vencerá, Prefeito Pinheiro No 4, Vice Mária Author: Luiz Andrade Publisher: Gráfica Borges Place: Bezerros, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Eleição 92 para vereador Jurandi Noberto Author: Tiago Ramos da Silva Publisher: unknown Place: Passira, PE., ca. 1992. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Editora do povo, a voz do povo na Câmara Author: Dodó Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O bêbado amuado, um trecho da minha vida Author: Severino Celestino dos Santos Group: Alcoólicos Anônimos Publisher: Gráfica Borges Place: Sairé, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O socialismo morreu? Author: Medeiros Braga Publisher: Educação Popular em Verso., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Doutor Luís Invani de Amorim Araújo uma trajetória luminosa Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Publisher: Academia Brasileira de Literatura de Cordel Place: Rio de Janeiro, RJ., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Mena: madrinha dos poetas do Brasil Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Publisher: G. F. da Silva Place: Rio de Janeiro, RJ., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Morte de Daniella Perez emociona o mundo Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Publisher: G. F. da Silva Place: Rio de Janeiro, RJ., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O gênio do Doutor Francisco Agenor Ribeiro da Silva Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Publisher: Academia Brasileira de Literatura de Cordel Place: Rio de Janeiro, RJ., 1992. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O bárbaro assassinato de Daniella Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Publisher: A. A. dos Santos Place: Campina Grande, Paraíba Other: acrostic, AALVES., 1993. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A história de Bento Leite ressuscitado da morte Author: Edmundo Soares Neto Illustrator: signed Sinézio Alves 1991 Publisher: Casa do Cantador do Brasil Place: Ceilândia, DF. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Euclides da Cunha e Os Sertões Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed XILO ERIVALDO Publisher: Academia Brasileira de Literatura de Cordel., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O mundo atual Author: José de Jesus Publisher: unknown Place: Monte Santo, BA., 1992. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Do agreste a mangue seco Author: José Arnaldo da Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A alma de Lampião faz misérias no nordeste Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A volta do pavão misterioso Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: 2a edição; acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Vaquejada de sete peões prá derrubar uma mineira Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: F. M. Nordestino Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Saci e bicho folaraz no reino da bicharada Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O sapo que desgraça o Corinthians Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed M Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Receitas de cachaça com folhas do Dr. Sabitudinho para curar doença Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Profecias de conselheiro, o sertão já virou mar Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: 3a edição; acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A praça é da poesia e arte na república Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed J.K. Suzuki Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Carta de um pau-de-arara apaixonado pra sua noiva Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed JERONIMO Publisher: Cachimba Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Corinthians não é mais aquêle do sapo cururu Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed M Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O crioulo doido que era um poeta popular Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed J.BARROS Publisher: Cacimbinha Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O frio de São Paulo está desmoralizado Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: Horóscopo das bichas Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: unknown Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1977. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O japonês que ficou roxo pela mulata Author: Franklin Maxado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: unknown Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A mulher que fez a barba do marido apulso Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: signed Sinézio Alves Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Place: Salvador, Bahia Other: 5a edição; acrostic, RODOLFO., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A língua da mulher faladeira Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Place: Salvador, Bahia Other: 6a edição., 1976. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O valentão de Jaquié Author: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: R. C. Cavalcante Place: Salvador, Bahia., 1975. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A filha imortal de J.K. Author: José João dos Santos "Mestre Azulão" Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: O canhão que atirou do contra, História da Guerra de 1914 Author: Abraão Batista Publisher: A. Batista Place: Juazeiro do Norte., 1991. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: História da minha vida no campo do álcool Author: unknown Publisher: Gráfica Borges Grupo: Alcoólicos Anônimos Place: Sairé, PE., after 1950. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: As hidrelétricas no Xingu Author: João de Castro Illustrator: Francé de Castro Edition: GRUCALT/SOPOCOBA Publisher: SOPREN Place: Altimira, Pará., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: A vingança de um inocente Author: João Firmino Cabral Illustrator: signed Adelmo Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Place: São Paulo, SP Other: acrostic, FIRMINO., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Title: História do valente Vilela Author: João Matins de Athayde Illustrator: signed Adelmo Publisher: Editora Luzeiro Limitada Place: São Paulo, SP., 1989. (Box 23, Folder 2)